[ narrator ] What you are about to see is inspired by true events .
According to the FBI ,
there are an estimated 1.4 million violent crimes
in America each year .
On the night of February 11 , 2005 ,
Kristen McKay and James Hoyt
left a friend 's wedding reception
and returned to the Hoyt family 's summer home .
The brutal events that took place there
are still not entirely known .
[ car engine starting ]
[ operator on phone ] 911 , what 's your emergency ?
[ Jordan gasping ]
911 , what 's your emergency ? Are you there ?
[ Jordan crying ] There ... There are people here .
[ operator ] Okay , calm down .
Where are you ? What 's your address ?
[ Jordan ] I don 't know .
[ operator ] Are you in danger ?
[ Jordan ] Yes . Yes .
[ operator ] What 's your name ?
Jordan .
We need help .
[ operator ] Okay . Can you tell me what street you 're on ?
[ Jordan ] I don 't know where we are .
[ operator ] Jordan , who are you with ?
[ Jordan ] We went into the house . We found people .
[ Jordan stuttering ]
[ operator ] You found who , Jordan ? Who did you find ?
[ Jordan ] There 's blood on the walls .
Help us ! Help us !
[ operator ] Jordan . Jordan , calm down .
[ Jordan ] It 's everywhere .
[ operator ] Jordan , what happened ?
[ Jordan ] There 's blood everywhere .
[ car door slams shut ]
[ door opening ]
[ keys rattling ]
[ door closes ]
â  ª Oh where you lay â  ª
â  ª Your head tonight â  ª
â  ª I 'll roll away alone â  ª
â  ª And close on down ... â  ª
When did you do all this ?
Uh , today .
With Mike .
When you were with the girls .
I thought you 'd like it .
â  ª And we 'll pretend ... â  ª
You can have this room . I 'm gonna get set up out there .
[ James sighs ]
Yeah , I don 't know about the tub .
Didn 't know if the roses go in first or after .
Uh ... Yeah , I don 't know either .
[ soft chuckle ]
Here .
Let me .
- Thank you . - Okay .
Mike , it 's me . Um , we 're at the house now .
I ... I know you 're fucking drunk ,
well , maybe you 're asleep now , but ...
[ water splashing ]
Uh ...
I 'll tell you when I see you , but things ...
They didn 't work out the way I planned at all .
Um ... I 'm going to need you to come out here and get me .
Uh , just whenever you wake up in the morning .
I 'm going to give her the car . Just ...
call me when you get this , okay ?
I know , I know it 's a bitch to come all the way out here
but , sorry , this sucks .
Okay .
[ laughing ]
- Hi . - Hi .
Come outside with me .
I only wanted to dance with you .
We 're dancing right now .
Jerk .
- You 're a jerk . - You 're a jerk .
Oh , it 's freezing . Let 's get in the car .
Wait a second .
What ?
I just want to tell you something .
What do you wanna tell me ?
I remember the first time I ever saw you .
[ owl hoots ]
[ clock chiming ]
[ sighs ]
It 's really nice , everything you did .
It 's beautiful .
[ soft chuckle ]
Yeah .
Here .
I can 't keep it . I can 't take it back .
Please .
Just take it , please .
[ cork popping ]
Here .
[ blowing softly ]
Your clothes are in the bedroom , if you want .
I wanna wear this .
You know , I only get to wear it tonight .
It makes me feel pretty .
You are pretty .
I 'm so sorry it wasn 't the way you thought it would be .
I 'm really sorry .
Well , what do we do now ?
I don 't know .
[ sighs ]
I 'm just not ready yet .
Okay .
[ sighs ]
[ sniffles ]
- James , please ... - Please .
- Talk to me . - Christ .
This is embarrassing .
[ " At My Window Sad and Lonely " by Wilco playing ]
â  ª At my window sad and lonely â  ª
â  ª Oft times do I think of thee â  ª
â  ª Sad and lonely and I wonder â  ª
â  ª Do you ever think of me ? â  ª
â  ª Every day is sad and lonely â  ª
â  ª Every night is sad and blue â  ª
â  ª Do you ever think of me My darling â  ª
â  ª As you sail that ocean blue ? â  ª
You 're my girl .
â  ª At my window , sad and lonely â  ª
â  ª I stand and stare Across the sea â  ª
â  ª I , sad and lonely â  ª
[ gasps ]
[ knocking on door ]
What is it , like , 4 : 00 in the morning ?
[ knocking continues ]
Hi .
Hello .
[ light switch clicking ]
Is Tamara here ?
No . No , you got the wrong house .
You sure ?
Yeah . I 'm sorry .
See you later .
That was weird .
Yeah .
People get lost out here . Should I go get her ?
[ Kristen ] She seemed okay .
I mean , I think she would 've said if she wasn 't .
[ Kristen whispering ] It 's cold out there .
[ record popping sounds ]
I 'm out of cigarettes .
I 'll go get you some more .
I didn 't ... I didn 't mean that . You don 't have to .
I 'll just go to sleep . I 'm tired , anyway .
No , you won 't .
I 'll try .
It 's all right , I want to drive for a while , anyway .
Let me light you a fire .
I was thinking when you were taking a bath .
I want you to take the car back tomorrow .
What do you mean ?
I don 't think a road trip 's a good idea right now .
I called Mike . He 's gonna come out and get me in the morning .
Are you sure that 's what you want ?
[ blowing ]
Yeah .
Okay , I 'll be back .
If you want , we can talk some more .
We don 't have to .
Okay ?
You gonna be okay here ?
- Yeah , I 'll be fine . - Okay .
Thanks for lighting me a fire .
Sure .
[ bottle rattles ]
[ " Sprout and the Bean " by Joanna Newsom playing ]
â  ª I slept all day â  ª
â  ª Awoke with distaste â  ª
â  ª And I railed â  ª
- â  ª And I raved â  ª - [ playing piano ]
â  ª That the difference between â  ª
â  ª The sprout and the bean â  ª
â  ª It is a golden ring â  ª
â  ª It is a twisted string â  ª
â  ª And you can ask The counselor â  ª
â  ª You can ask the king â  ª
â  ª And they 'll say The same thing â  ª
[ bang on door ]
â  ª And it 's a funny thing â  ª
â  ª Should we go outside ? â  ª
â  ª Should we break some bread ? â  ª
[ bang on door ]
â  ª Are y 'interested ? â  ª
[ knocking ]
Hello ?
[ woman ] Is Tamara home ?
You already came by here .
[ woman ] Are you sure ?
[ footsteps ]
[ chimes ringing ]
[ smoldering ]
[ coughs ]
[ beeping ]
[ beeping stops ]
[ bang on door ]
[ knocking on door ]
[ dialing ]
[ phone beeps ]
Oh , come on .
[ beeps ]
[ knocking on door ]
[ dialing ]
James , where are you ?
That girl came back .
That girl , I mean , she keeps knocking on the door .
What do you mean ? I heard her voice .
No , I didn 't open the door .
I don 't know .
The battery is dead . I 'm charging it right now .
Okay , okay .
I just want you to come home , okay ?
No , I 'm fine , but just , you know , hurry .
How far away are you ?
Okay .
Will you just stay on the phone with me ?
[ beeps ]
James ?
[ door closes ]
[ phone dialing ]
[ bang on door ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ rumbling ]
[ knocking on door ]
[ nervously sobbing ]
[ door rattling ]
[ whispering ] This isn 't happening . This isn 't happening .
[ metal clanking ]
[ metallic grating ]
[ screaming ]
[ record repeating ]
[ banging on door ]
[ thudding , clattering ]
[ screams ] Go away !
[ banging on door ]
[ sobbing ]
[ record stops ]
[ footsteps approaching ]
- Jamie . - Kristen .
There is someone out there .
- What are you doing ? What ? - There 's something ...
- They 'll hear you . - Stop , stop , stop . Shh !
What happened to your hand ?
[ Kristen sobbing ]
Stop . Stop !
Come here , come here . Sit down . Sit down , sit down , sit down .
How do you know somebody 's out there ?
I saw a man at the back door . He 's wearing a mask .
What do you mean ? Like a ski mask ?
- What ? - I don 't know . A fucking mask !
- I don 't know . - Okay , okay . Calm down .
- Jamie , I 'm so scared . - Okay .
Don 't go out there . Please , don 't go .
- Please , stop . - Just stay here .
I 'm right here . Stop .
No one out here .
Nobody . Come here .
- [ sobbing ] - Come here .
It 's okay , there 's nothing here .
What do you wanna do ?
I don 't know .
Kristen ?
Kristen , what is it ?
She 's watching us .
[ James ] She looks like a ghost .
You want me to go talk to her ?
- They don 't wanna talk . - Well , they want something .
People just don 't stand out there staring at us like that .
They want something .
- Shit . - What ?
I left my phone in the car , I 'm gonna go get it .
You can 't go out there .
Why ?
One of them came in here and took my phone .
Kristen , nobody came in here .
[ Kristen ] She 's gone .
Fuck !
[ noise ]
Shit !
[ exclaims ]
[ banging ]
[ dog yelping ]
What do you want ?
All right , get the fuck out of here !
[ footsteps ]
[ softly ] James !
Kristen , go back inside .
- What 's happening ? - Kristen ...
[ banging ]
Kristen , go .
[ door closes ]
[ creaking ]
Jesus Christ , what are you doing ?
I 'm sorry . I 'm waiting for you .
I want you to get your things . Put your shoes on .
Did you find your phone ?
No , I told you , they took my phone .
- Babe , I put it in your bag . - James , it 's not in the bag .
I plugged it into the wall ,
and when I came back it was gone .
It 's just , I don 't understand . We checked the whole house ,
and nobody in here .
Let me see your hand .
What are you thinking ?
Since we 've been here , I haven 't heard a dog bark ,
a car pass , nothing .
Just us and them .
Why are they doing this ?
Kristen , I don 't want you to think about that , okay ?
Don 't think about it . Doesn 't matter right now .
We don 't need a reason if they come through that door .
Okay ?
- What is it ? - It 's my phone .
We gotta get out of here .
Shit .
- [ Kristen ] Who is that ? - [ James ] I don 't know .
[ engine revving ]
Get out of the car .
[ car revving ]
[ Kristen screaming ]
Come on .
[ car honking ]
[ exhales ]
James , we need a gun .
I 'm looking .
Does your dad have a gun ?
Kristen , I 'm looking .
There was one here when I was a kid . He always hid it .
Let 's go to the bedroom .
[ Kristen ] Oh , my God !
[ banging ]
- [ Kristen ] What are you doing ? - Looking for bullets .
Stop . I got them , I got them .
I don 't know how to use this thing .
What do you mean ?
I 'm not sure I even know how to load it .
But you said you used to hunt with your dad .
No , I never did .
It was just something that I said .
When I open the door , I just want you to run , okay ?
[ screaming ]
Block the door , block the door .
[ Kristen screaming ]
Push !
Come on .
We 're not gonna fucking die here .
We 're gonna sit here , we 're gonna wait for
the fucking cops to come , or whatever ,
but we 're not gonna fucking die .
[ rumbling ]
[ footsteps ]
[ " Mama Tried " by Merle Haggard playing ]
â  ª The first thing I remember knowing â  ª
â  ª Was a lonesome Whistle blowing â  ª
â  ª And a young un 's dream of Growing up to ride â  ª
[ phone dialing ]
Yo , Jimmy James . What 's up , buddy ?
It 's Mike . Listen , man , I 'm outside .
I - I got here early .
I just decided to come out , and you know ,
just be here for you as soon as I possibly could ,
because you know how I like to wait on you
hand and fucking foot .
[ exclaims ]
What the fuck ?
[ chimes ringing ]
[ music continues playing ]
â  ª I turned twenty-one in prison Doing life without parole â  ª
â  ª No one could steer me right But Mama tried , Mama tried â  ª
â  ª Mama tried â  ª
Hello ?
â  ª But her pleading , I denied â  ª
â  ª That leaves only me to blame ' Cause Mama tried â  ª
Jimmy ?
Kristen ?
â  ª The first thing I remember knowing â  ª
â  ª Was a lonesome Whistle blowing â  ª
â  ª And a young un 's dream of Growing up to ride â  ª
â  ª On a freight train Leaving town â  ª
â  ª Not knowing where I 'm bound â  ª
â  ª And no one could change My mind but Mama tried â  ª
â  ª One and only rebel child From a family , meek and mild â  ª
â  ª My Mama seemed to know What lay in store â  ª
â  ª Despite all my Sunday learning
â  ª Towards the bad I kept on turning '
â  ª Till Mama couldn 't hold me anymore â  ª
â  ª I turned twenty-one in prison Doing life without parole â  ª
â  ª No one could steer me right But Mama tried , Mama tried â  ª
â  ª Mama tried To raise me better â  ª
â  ª But her pleading , I denied â  ª
â  ª That leaves only me to blame ' Cause Mama tried â  ª
â  ª Dear old Daddy , rest his soul Left my mom a heavy load â  ª
â  ª She tried so very hard To fill his shoes â  ª
â  ª Working hours without rest Wanted me to have the best â  ª
â  ª She tried to raise me right But I refused â  ª
â  ª I turned twenty-one in prison Doing life without parole â  ª
â  ª No one could steer me right But Mama tried , Mama tried â  ª
â  ª Mama tried To raise me better â  ª
â  ª But her pleading , I denied â  ª
â  ª That leaves only me to blame ' Cause Mama tried â  ª
[ song ends ]
Hello ?
Kristen , I shot him .
He didn 't have a mask .
What ?
Why didn 't he have a fucking mask ?
What do you mean , he didn 't have a mask ?
James ?
[ gasps ]
What ?
Oh , God !
- What is it ? - [ James crying ] Stay there .
James , answer me .
Oh , fuck !
What ?
Don 't .
- Ow . Get off of me . Stop it . - It 's Mike . Mike .
- Please don 't look . It 's Mike . - [ sobbing ] Oh , God .
Baby , it 's not your fault .
He was my best friend . He 's my best friend .
He was my best friend . What did I do ?
[ Kristen sobbing ]
[ Kristen coughing ]
[ coughing ]
[ Kristen ] Where are you going ?
I 'm gonna go outside . I want you to hide somewhere .
What are you talking about ?
There 's an old radio out in the barn ,
I 'm gonna try and call for help .
I don 't know what else to do .
It 's okay , I 'm gonna come right back for you .
Listen , I want you to go , and I want you to hide there .
I 'll keep them away . I 'll come find you .
James , no . I want to come with you .
Kristen , please , it 'll be okay , I promise .
I 'll be fine .
[ whispering ] Be careful . James .
[ car door opens ]
[ breathing heavily ]
Oh , shit !
[ footsteps approaching ]
[ gunshot ]
James ?
Ah ! [ crying in pain ]
Oh , fuck !
[ breathing heavily ]
[ clanking ]
James ?
[ thud ]
[ clattering ]
[ clanking ]
[ man indistinct on radio ]
[ whispering ] Hello ?
[ normal ] Hello ?
[ crying ] Can anybody hear me ?
[ voice approaching ]
[ clattering ]
[ thudding ]
[ creaking ]
[ footsteps ]
[ thudding ]
[ clanking ]
[ banging ]
[ man on radio ] This is K-50-XV .
Hello ?
Can you hear me ? Hello ?
Please , answer me .
[ man indistinct on radio ]
- Help me . - Where are you ?
[ screaming ]
[ clattering ]
[ twigs snapping ]
[ thud ]
[ piano playing ]
[ clattering ]
[ screaming ]
No !
He 's gonna kill you .
[ rattling ]
Why are you doing this to us ?
[ clanking ]
[ coughs ]
[ whispers ] James .
You 're gonna die .
[ James ] Kristen , run !
[ screaming ]
Let me out !
[ James ] Kristen ! Run !
Jamie !
[ screaming ]
[ man breathing deeply ]
[ Kristen screaming ]
[ Kristen sobbing ]
Why are you doing this to us ?
[ Dollface ] Because you were home .
I love you .
Baby !
No ! Please ! No !
No ! Please !
You don 't have to do this . Please !
You can stop now . You ... Please ! No !
Please , listen to me . Please .
You can stop now . You don 't have to do this .
[ Kristen screaming ] No !
[ groans ]
[ Kristen ] Baby , look at me .
Look at my face .
Don 't look , please .
Please ! Please ! Please , don 't !
No !
[ Kristen ] No !
[ Kristen sobbing , exclaims in pain ]
[ phone ringing ]
[ phone continues ringing ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ floorboards creaking ]
[ sobbing ]
[ vehicle approaching ]
[ woman ] Can I have one ?
Are you a sinner ?
Sometimes .
[ woman ] It 'll be easier next time .
[ record popping ]
[ screaming ]
[ ambient music playing ]
[ music fades out ]